# Carla Sahagun

DMV area | 571-982-9406 | daniela.sahagun03@gmail.com

https://github.com/itacamba | https://medium.com/@daniela.sahagun03 | https://linkedin.com/in/carla-sahagun

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Dependable and detail-oriented software engineer experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript-based programming and a background in customer service. Possess strong skills in organization and communication. Comfortable with working in a fast-paced environment, cooperating with a team and delivering exceptional experiences. Known for a strong work ethic, professional demeanor and the ability to learn new technologies quickly.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Git.

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Find a Personal Chef "Cheffed" - Github | Demo

Find specialized chefs and request him/her to cook a specific dish for you and your family.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Integrated a user friendly interface with Semantic UI and CSS3 to make the user experience intuitive.
- Added a Ruby on Rails API backend and a Reactis frontend.

# Pictionary Real Time "Flationary" - Github | Demo

Create or join a game, draw the given word and your friends will have to guess, the guesser earns a point and becomes the drawer.

- Helped with the logic in the backend to make a real time-like app with long polling.
- Created wireframes for user experience purposes
- Implemented CSS3 to the frontend, and choose color palette

# Adopt a Dog, Animal Shelter app "Furrever" - Github | Demo

Shows all available pets for adoption, a user can adopt and rename a pet, that pet will be no longer for adoption in the shelter.

- Created and implemented a Ruby on Rails API backend to save information about users and pets.
- Worked with Semantic UI as a CSS framework to enhance the view of the client.
- Implemented the logic to make a pet be adopted only once, and making it unavailable once adopted.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Eddie Merlot's** Ashburn, Virginia 01/2020 - Present Server

- Offered advice for entree, wine pairing and dessert items.
- Promptly deliver dishes to ensure proper temperature upon consumption.
- Memorized and recalled daily and seasonal specials.
- Delivered exceptional service by greeting and serving customers in a timely, friendly manner.

## 21 Great American Bistro

Fairfax, Virginia 03/2018 - 2019

Server / Bartender

- Maintained detailed knowledge of menu items and ingredients to drive sales.
- Provided recommendations about food and wine, and introduced daily specials.
- Maintained impeccable customer service to ensure guest satisfaction and dining experience.
- Demonstrated the ability to multi-task at a fast pace environment while dealing with various situations/individuals.

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School City, State 03/2020 - 06/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program